Guide to the Hewlett Diversity Archive, 1912 - 1999
Hewlett Diversity Archive, 1912 - 1999
- Series 2: Interviews, Transcripts, and Panel Recordings
  - Interview Tapes
    - Beckham, Edgar, and Willard McRae, Part II (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Boyer, Ronald, October 18, year unknown (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Budryk, Peter, August 13, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
      Two tapes.
    - Chapman, Peter, class of 1987, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Cheigh, Eileen, class of 1991, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Clendeninn, Neil, class of 1971, undated (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
    - Cruz Jacobs, Lillian, class of 1976, April 19, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Cruz, Lillian, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Cutler, Cheryl, April 9, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
    - Dawson, Ken, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Davar, Tamina, class of 1990, November 19, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Dunn, Ernest, class of 1959, August 15, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - President Ted Etherington, August 8, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
      3 tapes.
    - Listening copies of tapes in Box 10, Folders 1-17, made January, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 2-4)
    - Arthur Gaither, class of 1975, May (?) 18, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Dwight Greene, class of 1970, March 10, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Doris Hallie, August 16, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Grant Hawkins, class of 1971, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Hope Hill, class of 1974, March 24, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 6-9)
      4 tapes.
    - Edward Jackson, November 29, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Richard Jasper, class of 1973, undated (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
      2 tapes.
    - Willie Kerr, August 5-20, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 13-16)
    - Michael Kim, class of 1986, August 9, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Robert Kirkpatrick, class of 1960, July 24, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - D. Kwok, July 31, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Charisse Lillie, class of 1973, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Professor Jerome Long, August 11, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Professor John Maguire, August 1995 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Professor David McAllester, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Bertha McRae, October 26, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Randy Miller, class of 1970, May 15, year unknown (Box 12, Folder 8)
      On the Black Repertory Theatre.
    - Joan Morgan, class of 1987 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      On Minister Farrakhan.
    - Chris Rodriguez, class of 1974 (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
    - Professor Yoshiko Samuel, July 24, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Listening copy of interview in Box 12, Folder 12, made January 2001 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Peter Santana, class of 1973, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Nathan Scott, July 25, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Ted Shaw, undated (Box 12, Folder 15-16)
    - James Stewart, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Chuck Stone, class of 1948, July 1995 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Professor David Swift, July 27, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Francis Thomas, class of 1936, July 25, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - James Thomas, class of 1961, August 16, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Professor Willard Walker, July 24, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Linda Wong, class of 1990, August 5, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Symposium Tapes
    - Symposium #1, Intro, Johnson (Box 13, Folder 7)
      Side A.
    - Symposium #2, Dialogue responses (Box 13, Folder 7)
      Side B.
    - Symposium #3, James Stewart, Larry Neal (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Symposium #4, Larry Neal (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Symposium #5, Telera Nash (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Symposium #6, Nash, Shepp (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Symposium #7, Archie Schepp, Paula Marshall (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Symposium #8, Paula Marshall, cont. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Panel Discussion Tapes
    - Panel Discussion 1 (Intro, Bennet) (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Panel Discussions 1 and 2 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Panel Discussion 2, (1) Fair, (2) Sanchez (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - (side A) Larry Neal (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - (side B) Panel discussion 3, D. Johnson (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - (side A) Panel Discussion #3,Vinc. Hardiner (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - (side B) Sonia Sanchez (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - (side A) Intro, Doug Johnson, James Stewart (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - (side B) Panel Discussions 1,2,3 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Panel Discussions 1,2,3 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Poetry Reading Tapes, etc.
    - Tape 2: (A) Intro, D. Johnson, A. Schepp, P. Marshall, E. Pomare (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Tape 2: (B) S. Sanchez, Poetry Readings 1 & 2 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Tape 2: Sonia Sanchez, Poetry Reading 1 & 2 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Tape 3: Intro – D. Sonnson, James Stewart (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Tape 3: (A) Sanchez, Poetry 1 & 2 (cont) (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Tape 4: (side A) Larry Neal (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Tape 4: (side B) Texeira Nash (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Tape 4: Larry Neal, Texiera Nash (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Number 5, Intro, D. Johnson, Archie Schepp, P. Marshall, E. Poinare (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Tape 5: (side A) Texeira Nash (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Tape 6: Intro, D. Johnson, Archie Schepp (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - (side A) Poetry Readings, Archie Schepp, Veronica Sanchez (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - (side B) Larry Neal (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Tape 7: Paula Marshall, Eleo Poihare (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Tape 7: Sanchez (cont) (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Transcribed Interviews
    - Edgar Beckham, class of 1958, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Douglas Bennet, class of 1959, September 15, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Peter Budryk (Director of Upward Bound, 1968-99), August 13, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - President Emeritus Colin Campbell, April 6, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - President Emeritus Colin Campbell, September 21, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Professor Anthony Chambers, July 23, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Peter Chapman, class of 1987, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Eileen Cheigh, class of 1991, December 11, 199[?] (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Lillian Cruz (Jacobs), class of 1976, [April 19, 1986] (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Professor Cheryl Cutler, April 9, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Melvin Dixon, class of 1971, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Ernest Dunn, class of 1959, August 15, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - President Ted Etherington, August 8, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Karl Furstenberg, class of 1967 (Dean of Admission, 1977-90), September 23, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Dwight Greene, class of 1970, March 10, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Doris Hallie, August 16, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Hope Hill, class of 1974, March 24, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - John C. Hoy, undated (incomplete draft) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - John C. (Jack) Hoy, class of 1955, November 19, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Jack Hoy ’55 (Dean of Admission, 1964-1970), September 10, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Edward Jackson, November 29, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Evan Jacobs, class of 1973, September 24, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Willie Kerr, August 5-7, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Michael Kim, class of 1986, August 9, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Robert Kirkpatrick, class of 1960, July 24, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Daphne Kwok, class of 1984, July 31, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Charisse Lillie, class of 1973, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Jerome Long (Professor of Religion, 1971-1997), August 11, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Professor John Maguire, August, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Ron McMullen (Professor of Psychology, 1969-1975), August 26, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Janine Montero (Professor and Dean, 1973-1993), September 2, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Joan Morgan, class of 1987, October 22, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Gayle Pemberton (Professor of English and African-American Studies, 1994-1999), September 29, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Anna Rhee, class of 1983, August 14, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Robert Rosenbaum (Professor of Math emeritius), August 20, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Professor Yoshiko Samuel, July 24, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Nathan Scott, July 25, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Ted Shaw, class of 1976, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Chuck Stone, class of 1948, July 1995 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Includes photo.
    - Professor David Swift, July 27, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - James Thomas, class of 1961, August 16, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Richard Vann (Professor of History and Letters, 1964-1999), September 13, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Professor Willard Walker, July 24, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Linda Wong, class of 1990, August 5, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Jeremy Zwelling (Professor of Religion, 1967-1999), August 17, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Series 3: Material Relating to the Hewlett Project
  - Hewlett Plurality and Unity Project at Wesleyan
    Items arranged chronologically.
    Rushdy’s Housing Tutorial papers are arranged by topic in the Minority Student / Special Interest Housing section.
    - Grant proposal ($100,000) and reports, 1994-1998 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Information sources for Archive (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Kerr, William; information available from (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Indices of Wesleyan publications
      - Wesleyan Argus, [people of color / student protests?], 1960-1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Student protest articles, 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Ankh index (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Research project, summer 1995 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Faculty survey, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Progress reports, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Evaluation, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Residential component, Hewlett Plurality and Unity Program, [1996] (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Summer readings for Hewlett Fellows, 1996
      - Section I – AFAM 201: Sample Marking (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Section II – Revolt of the Privileged, by Alford Young (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Section III – Mechanics of Oral History (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Section IV – Afro-American Studies, by Nathan Huggins (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Argus assignment, summer 1996 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Journals and records, Hewlett Fellows, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Elmore, Lauren Britt (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Krieg, Kristine (Box 8, Folder 3-5)
      - Lewis, Nikki (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Unknown #1 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Unknown #2 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Exhibit, summer 1999
    - Photographs, Mellon Fellows (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Angier, Jessica, class of 1995
      - Lewis, Nikki, class of 1997
      - Richardson, Kerri, class of 1993
      - Von Vacano, Diego, class of 1992
  - Organizations / Events related to Diversity in Higher Education
    Arranged by subject.
    - Kettering Foundation (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Pluralism and Unity Conference, held in California, February 5-7, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Pluralism and Unity Conference, final report (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - UCI (University of California at Irvine), Center for Educational Partnership (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Diversity, General
    - Asian Americans, general (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
    - Connecticut Council for Black Students and Professionals (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Minorities in higher education (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Race and diversity, articles, 1988-1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)